<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Blockchain Blog</string>
    <string name="app">A blockchain is a distributed database or ledger that is shared among the nodes of a computer network. As a database, a blockchain stores information electronically in digital format. Blockchains are best known for their crucial role in cryptocurrency systems, such as Bitcoin, for maintaining a secure and decentralized record of transactions. The innovation with a blockchain is that it guarantees the fidelity and security of a record of data and generates trust without the need for a trusted third party. One key difference between a typical database and a blockchain is how the data is structured. A blockchain collects information together in groups, known as blocks, that hold sets of information. Blocks have certain storage capacities and, when filled, are closed and linked to the previously filled block, forming a chain of data known as the blockchain. All new information that follows that freshly added block is compiled into a newly formed block that will then also be added to the chain once filled. A database usually structures its data into tables, whereas a blockchain, as its name implies, structures its data into chunks (blocks) that are strung together. This data structure inherently makes an irreversible timeline of data when implemented in a decentralized nature. When a block is filled, it is set in stone and becomes a part of this timeline. Each block in the chain is given an exact timestamp when it is added to the chain.</string>
    <string name="app3">A decentralized app or dApp offers the benefits of centralized cloud-based apps like Google Docs, but without the need for cloud datacenters. Using the same blockchain technology like cryptocurrencies, ICOs, and NFTs, dApps offer unique security and privacy advantages.A decentralized app or dApp offers the benefits of centralized cloud-based apps like Google Docs, but without the need for cloud datacenters. Using the same blockchain technology like cryptocurrencies, ICOs, and NFTs, dApps offer unique security and privacy advantages. The Benefits of dApp: Why were dApps invented in the first place? The answer involves concerns about the control big tech companies have over our data and how vulnerable centralized systems are.When your data is in one place, it means that if it goes down so does the service and so does the information. When a data center is hacked, all of the information is in one place. If a government decides to censor a service, they have one place to target. dApps promise to mitigate or eliminate all of these issues. Because they have no center, the service can’t be shut down or corrupted. If a dApp is open source, there’s no way to hide back doors in the code. Since dApps interact with the Ethereum blockchain to work, it also makes it easy to integrate cryptocurrency transactions into the app, making payments for services possible. Like Bitcoin, Ethereum is only pseudonymous, since there are ways to link the identity of a crypto-waller owner to that wallet. So dApps still have the same limitations as transacting with a centralized app that supports cryptocurrency payments. Decentralized apps can also make use of a so-called “sidechain”, which runs in parallel to the main blockchain, but has its own independent operation. The sidechain is connected to the main blockchain using a bridge and according to the official Ethereum sidechain document deploying dApps to a sidechain is virtually as easy (or hard) as deploying it to the main blockchain.</string>
    <string name="app2">When your data is in one place, it means that if it goes down so does the service and so does the information. When a data center is hacked, all of the information is in one place. If a government decides to censor a service, they have one place to target.

dApps promise to mitigate or eliminate all of these issues. Because they have no center, the service can’t be shut down or corrupted. If a dApp is open source, there’s no way to hide back doors in the code.

Since dApps interact with the Ethereum blockchain to work, it also makes it easy to integrate cryptocurrency transactions into the app, making payments for services possible. Like Bitcoin, Ethereum is only pseudonymous, since there are ways to link the identity of a crypto-waller owner to that wallet.

So dApps still have the same limitations as transacting with a centralized app that supports cryptocurrency payments.

Decentralized apps can also make use of a so-called “sidechain”, which runs in parallel to the main blockchain, but has its own independent operation. The sidechain is connected to the main blockchain using a bridge and according to the official Ethereum sidechain document deploying dApps to a sidechain is virtually as easy (or hard) as deploying it to the main blockchain.The History of Cryptocurrency
The first decentralized digital cryptocurrency can arguably be traced back to “bit gold” (not to be confused with Bitgold), which was worked on by Nick Szabo between 1998 and 2005 but was never implemented.

Although bit gold is widely considered the first precursor to bitcoin, cryptocurrency pioneer David Chaum’s company DigiCash (a company founded in 1989 which attempted to innovate digital currency), Wei Dai’s b-money (a conceptual system published in 1998 which Satoshi cites it in the Bitcoin white paper), and “e-gold” (a centralized digital currency that started in 1996) are all notable early mentions.With that history noted, modern digital currency starts in 2008 when Satoshi Nakamoto (an anonymous person and/or group) released their paper detailing what would become Bitcoin.

Bitcoin became the first decentralized digital coin when it was created in 2008. It then went public in 2009.

As of 2020, Bitcoin is the most commonly known and used cryptocurrency. Meanwhile, other coins including Ethereum (ETH), Ripple (XRP), Litecoin (LTC), and more are all notable mentions.

Given the popularity of Bitcoin as well as its history, the term “altcoin” is sometimes used to describe alternative cryptocurrencies to bitcoin (especially coins with small market caps).

As of January 2015, there were over 500 different types of cryptocurrencies – or altcoins – for trade in online markets. However, only 10 of them had market capitalizations over $10 million.

As of September 2017, there were over 1,100 cryptocurrencies and the total market capitalization of all cryptocurrencies reached an all-time high surpassing $60 billion! Then, by December 2017, the total market cap reached $600 billion (a multiple of 10 in only two months).

As of April 2021, there were over 6,700 cryptocurrencies and the total market capitalization of all cryptocurrencies reached an all-time high surpassing $2 trillion!

The total amount of coins continues to grow while the market cap ebbs and flows, but one can clearly see the direction of the trend over time toward more coins and a higher total market cap.

Although the future is uncertain, cryptocurrency is proving itself to be more than just a fad. Today cryptocurrency is shaping up to be a growing market that (despite the pros and cons) is likely here for the long haul.</string>
</resources>